# CONTACT

- **(**916) 817 9230
- joshharrison626@gmail.com
- Caldwell, ID, 83607
- http://www.linkedin.com/i n/jjharrison
- https://joshharrison626.git hub.io/portfolio/

# **SKILLS**

- HTML, CSS, SCSS
- Responsive Web Design
- Wireframing and Prototyping
- Web Accessibility Standards
- Assistive Technology
- JavaScript (Native, Libraries, and Frameworks)
- UI Frameworks (React)
- Reusable UI Components (Material-UI, Custom)
- Figma (Dev Mode)
- Documentation, Presentation, and Teaching
- Creativity and Innovation

### **AWARDS**

Accessibility Champion - Subject Matter Expert (Intuit)
This award recognizes Intuit's
Accessibility leaders. They lead accessibility efforts for products and locations. They help guide product design and development for the future of Intuit.

# **JOSH HARRISON**

# UI / UX DEVELOPER

# **PROFILE**

UI/UX Developer with 9 years of experience creating streamlined and intuitive controls and user experiences by bridging the gap between programming and design. Talented at architecting and creating high-fidelity prototypes based off of lo- and hi-fidelity designs. Consistently employs understanding of web accessibility requirements and best practices.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Intuit, Boise, ID
Frontend Staff Software Engineer

August 2022 - Present

- Co-led a team of 4 junior web developers to deliver a seamless integrated experience with QuickBooks Online and QuickBooks Time using iframe APIs, React, JavaScript, and QuickBooks theming
- Created initial proof-of-concept and framework for the time tracking integration resulting in product delivery in 6 months vs 5 years using iframe APIs, React, and JQuery
- Built the first reusable plugin using React, HTML, and CSS for the time tracking integration to support theme-switching and design tokens that could be used across all Intuit products
- Worked across teams and three internal design systems to drive web and accessibility standards and adopt design system components and tokens
- Created prototypes using React, HTML, and CSS based off of customer interviews and lo-fi designs to support design/UX concepts, prove technical feasibility, or suggest alternatives

Intuit, Boise, ID August 2021 - August 2022
Time Tracking Accessibility Leader, Staff Software Engineer

- Built a culture for accessibility that consisted of ~120 volunteer champions across development, customer support, product management, design, and research
- Created and taught an accessibility awareness class to introduce the organization to customers with disabilities, assistive technologies, and role-specific guides
- Led customer interviews to learn how features were used with assistive technologies and report bugs
- Delivered Intuits 2nd VPAT by working with an external contractor to provide an accessibility audit and lead volunteers to remediate 15 features using Microsoft Accessibility Insights and axe DevTools
- · Cont'd on next page

#### **VOLUNTEER WORK**

https://chairthehope.org/ Active volunteer: international wheelchair distributions; participate in local projects, fundraising, and create corporate partnership opportunities

## **ARTICLES**

- Accessibility features in QuickBooks Time
- <u>Lessons Learned from an Intuit</u>
   <u>Accessibility Champion</u> Intuit
   Blog
- Proving accessibility is worth it with analytics - Intuit Blog

# WORK EXPERIENCE (CONT'D)

- Built a visually-hidden accessibility toolbar and custom keyboard shortcuts using React, HTML, and CSS and published an accessibility help guide to support customers using keyboards and screen readers
- Created a method of tracking keyboard analytics to prove accessibility usage, bug fixes, and feature discoverability; Published a blog describing the method and presented at Knowbility's AccessU 2021

Intuit, Boise, ID

February 2019 - August 2021

Sr. Software Engineer

- Led a small team of web and mobile engineers to deliver features based on location services
- Created and supported reusable web components to support location services and features
- Co-published a patent for determining location based on nearby devices (IPR-2011747US)

Intel, Hillsboro, OR

January 2015 - Januarry 2019

Web Developer

- Create and manage the marketing budget, ensuring efficient allocation of resources and optimizing ROI.
- Oversee market research to identify emerging trends, customer needs, and competitor strategies.
- Monitor brand consistency across marketing channels and materials.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **B.S.** in Network and Communication Management

DeVry University

GPA: 4.0

#### A.S. in Electrical and Computer Technology

DeVry University

GPA: 4.0